<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<resume>
    <person>
        <name>Christopher Dail</name>
        <street>162 Leonard Street</street>
        <city>Riverview</city>
        <province>NB</province>
        <postal-code>E1B 1K8</postal-code>
        <phone>506-871-8560</phone>
        <email>chrisdail@gmail.com</email>
        <citizen>Canadian and US citizen</citizen>
    </person>
    <objectives>
        <objective>To obtain employment with a software development company as a lead developer or architect.</objective>
        <!--
        <objective>To obtain employment in a technology management position that utilizes my development experience and background.</objective>
        -->
    </objectives>
    <work>
        <job>
            <title>Senior Software Architect</title>
            <dates>February 2008 to Present</dates>
            <company>iWave Software LLC.</company>
            <location>Moncton, NB</location>
            <description>Responsible for the initial architecture and design of the iWave Adapters product, a suite
                of tools to facilitate ITSM integration and Run Book Automation. Responsible for managing
                and providing the technical leadership for a small development team. Responsible for working
                with the Professional Services team, Product Support, Quality Assurance and Technical Writing.
            </description>
            <description>Primary task was to create and maintain the Adapters Web Services platform. Technologies
                used include Java, Groovy, Python Spring, Apache CXF, JAX-WS, JAXB and JPA.
            </description>
            <description>Responsible for the leading the architecture and design of the iWave Automator product, 
                a Business Process Integration and Run Book Automation engine.
            </description>
            <description>Primary tasks include adding Version Control support to the IDE (Subversion), performance
                improvements and architecture changes.
            </description>
        </job>
        <job>
            <title>Team Lead (Developer)</title>
            <dates>August 2006 to February 2008</dates>
            <company>Skywire Software (formerly Whitehill Technologies)</company>
            <location>Moncton, NB</location>
            <description>Responsible to provide the technical leadership of the XML Transport product, a
                document automation suite for Insurance companies. 
                Responsibilities also include refining requirements, researching new features and technologies, estimating work effort
                and providing leadership in the architecture, design and development of the product. Other duties include
                mentoring team members and providing product and technology training to other departments and customers.  
            </description>
            <description>Responsibilities also include maintaining an active development role on the team.
                See the next job (Developer II) for more information on the common development responsibilities.
            </description>
        </job>
        <job>
            <title>Developer II</title>
            <dates>August 2003 to August 2006</dates>
            <company>Whitehill Technologies, Inc.</company>
            <location>Moncton, NB</location>
            <description>Responsible for design, development, unit testing and maintenance of a large business
            application. Primary development technologies used consist of Java, Groovy, Spring, JUnit, XML, XSLT and XSL-FO. 
            Operating Systems developed for include Windows, Solaris, Linux and Z/OS.</description>
        </job>
        <!--
        <job>
            <title>Web Designer - 1 to 2 hours per week</title>
            <dates>December 1999 to January 2005</dates>
            <company>Convention of Atlantic Baptist Churches</company>
            <location>http://www.baptist-atlantic.ca</location>
            <description></description>
        </job>
        -->
        <job>
            <title>Software Developer (Co-op)</title>
            <dates>16 Months between September 2000 and August 2002</dates>
            <company>ASG Technologies Inc.</company>
            <location>Fredericton, NB</location>
            <description>Responsible for development and maintenance web based and stand alone applications 
            for the EnGuarde and Passwerks products using Java, C, C++, PHP, JSP, XML on Solaris, Linux 
            and BSD platforms. Responsibilities also included testing, build and install scripting
            and system administration tasks.</description>
        </job>
        <!--
        <job>
            <title>Co-Owner / Operator</title>
            <dates>April 2000 to January 2001</dates>
            <company>Geekbox Computers</company>
            <location>Fredericton, NB</location>
            <description>Responsible for routine operation of the business (computer and component sales), 
            maintenance and creation of an online storefront, including shopping cart facilities. Also responsible 
            for managing financial correspondence and customer relations.</description>
        </job>
        -->
        <job>
            <title>Programmer (Co-op)</title>
            <dates>January 2000 to April 2000, May 1999 to August 1999</dates>
            <company>NB Power - Point Lepreau Nuclear Generating Station</company>
            <location>Lepreau, NB</location>
            <description>Simulator Training Department.  Developed and maintained software for the nuclear
            power plant simulator.  Development done in Visual C++ and Visual Fortran on Windows NT and 
            Open VMS platforms.</description>
        </job>
        <!--
        <job>
            <title>Student Marker - CS 1073</title>
            <dates>September 1999 to April 2000</dates>
            <company>University of New Brunswick</company>
            <location>Saint John, NB</location>
            <description></description>
        </job>
        <job>
            <title>Bookstore Sales Clerk</title>
            <dates>AUGUST 1998 to JANUARY 2000</dates>
            <company>Baptist Bookroom</company>
            <location>Saint John, NB</location>
            <description></description>
        </job>
        <job>
            <title>Summer Youth Worker</title>
            <dates>JUNE 1998 to SEPTEMBER 1998</dates>
            <company>Forest Hills Baptist Church</company>
            <location>Saint John, NB</location>
            <description></description>
        </job>
        -->
    </work>
    <education>
        <!--
        Other stuff?
        XSLT, XSL-FO course
        AFP training
        J2EE training
        .NET training
        Design Patterns
        -->
        <school>
            <degree>Bachelor of Computer Science</degree>
            <dates>September 1998 - April 2003</dates>
            <institution>University of New Brunswick</institution>
            <location>Fredericton, NB</location>
            <description>Graduated with honors in Software Systems, Deans List and the Co-op program.</description>
        </school>
        <school>
            <degree>High School</degree>
            <dates>September 1995 - June 1998</dates>
            <institution>Saint John High School</institution>
            <location>Saint John, NB</location>
            <description>Graduated with high honors. International Baccalaureate courses taken in Mathematics, 
            Chemistry and Physics.</description>
        </school>
    </education>
    <skills>
        <!--
        Domain experience? Insurance/Document Automation, etc.
        -->
        <skill-set>
            <title>Soft Skills</title>
            <description>Ability to lead and manage small teams. Able to provide clear direction
            and foster teamwork. Strong verbal and written
            communication skills. Excellent team worker and problem solver.</description>
            <description>Experienced in teaching courses on programming languages, customer products, 
            XSLT and XSL-FO. Experienced in
            mentoring junior team members.</description>
        </skill-set>
        <!--
        <skill-set>
            <title>ITSM Skills</title>
            <description>Experienced developing and using Run Book Automation software. Experienced developing
                integration and automation adapters for ITSM applications including many
                Service Management and Event Management systems.
            </description>
        </skill-set>
        -->
        <skill-set>
            <title>Programming Languages</title>
            <description>Experienced programmer in Java, Groovy, Python and C/C++. Experience and basic knowledge of other languages
            include Ruby, Fortran, Assembler and .NET. Scripting experience includes
            Perl, sh, awk and Windows batch. Ability to learn new languages quickly.
            </description>
            <description>Knowledge of Software Engineering concepts such as unit testing, UML
            and design patterns.</description>
        </skill-set>
        <skill-set>
            <title>Development Technologies</title>
            <description>Experience using the Eclipse and Visual Studio development environments. Experience
            creating build processes using maven, ant and make. Experience setting up continuous integration
            environments using CruiseControl and Hudson. Experience using and administering version control
            systems including CVS, VSS and Subversion. Database development experience using ORM technologies
            such as JPA. Experience using databases: Oracle, IBM DB2, MS SQLServer,
            Ingres, Sybase, MySQL, PostgreSQL and Derby.</description>
            <description>Experiencing using WebServices, RMI and other clustering technologies.</description>
            <description>Extensive experience using XML technologies such as WSDL, JAX-WS, JAXB, XSLT, XSL-FO, SAX and DOM. Experience
            teaching a week long course on XSLT and XSL-FO. Experience
            using the Apache FOP, RenderX XEP and XSLFormatter renderers.</description>
            <description>Experience using document technologies such as AFP, PDF and PostScript.</description>
        </skill-set>
        <skill-set>
            <title>Web and J2EE Application Programming</title>
            <description>Experienced in server-side development using Spring and J2EE. Some experience in
            web development using Grails, jQuery (AJAX), JSP, Java Servlets and PHP.
            Experience using Apache and Tomcat webservers. Experience setting up and using JBoss,
            IBM WebSphere and BEA WebLogic application servers.
            </description>
        </skill-set>
        <skill-set>
            <title>Computer Networking and Infrastructure</title>
            <description>Very knowledgeable about operating systems, including various flavors of UNIX (Linux, 
            Solaris, AIX) and various flavors of Windows. Also some industry experience using Open VMS
            and Z/OS. </description>
            <description>Knowledge and experience in some system administration and networking.</description>
        </skill-set>
    </skills>
    <personal>
        <interests>Easy to get along with and quick learner. Interests include helping out at local church youth
            group, movies, video games, Hiking and playing music.</interests>
    </personal>
    <references>
        <!--
        <reference>
            <name>Name</name>
            <description>title</description>
            <description>company</description>
            <description>contact</description>
        </reference>
        -->
    </references>
</resume>
